## Sai Manichandana Devi Thumati

🔁 thumati.sa@northeastern.edu | 📊 <u>Chandana Thumati</u> | <u>Google Scholor</u>

#### **SUMMARY**

I am an upcoming MS in Computer Science student at Northeastern University, with interests in machine learning and deep learning. During my undergraduate studies, I developed AI-driven tools for analyzing complex datasets and published research on dental disease prediction using neural networks. Currently, I am a Graduate Quality Engineer at CBA and am passionate about driving technological advancements

## **EDUCATION**

## Master of Science (MS) | Computer Science

Northeastern University

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech) | Computer Science and Engineering

Amrita Vishwa Vidyapeetham

Starts on Sep 2024 Boston, MA, United States July 2019 - June 2023 Amritapuri, Kerala, India

#### EXPERIENCE

## **Associate Quality Engineer - Financial Crime Technology**

Banglore, Karnataka, India

April 2024 - Present

Commonwealth Bank of Australia

- Reponsible For Collecting and testing data using Teradata, SQL and related internal tools.
- Current Learning : Tableau. Scala, AWS

## IoT Intern - IoT & Automation Department

Jan 2023 - Nov 2023

Maersk Global Services Pvt Ltd

Banglore, Karnataka, India

- Developed the software simulators using Python language programming for multiple reefers (containers)
- · Conducted manual testing of end-to-end test scenarios for various reefers
- · Worked with remote and virtual environments during testing such as WSL, Mqtt server
- Created automated testing software in Python Language programming for multiple reefers which can reduce the human errors and time for testing
- Gained experience in writing and testing of software in Python language, serial communication, robot testing framework, mosquito server, unit testing, and mock serial in Python language.

## Java Intern (Remote)

May 2022 - June 2022

TiNet Business Solutions Pvt. Ltd

Banglore, Karnataka, India

- Proficiently acquired skills in JDBC with PostgreSQL, Spring framework, and Java Persistence API (JPA)
- Created comprehensive documentation on JDBC with PostgreSQL, Spring framework, and Java Persistence API technologies and actively supported project developers during demonstrations.
- Gained valuable insights into industrial technology requirements such as Security and Data Protection.

## **PUBLICATIONS**

#### **Conference Paper (peer - reviewed)**

SMD Thumati, K Dhanya, H Sathish, KCS Madan, S Rani. A Comparative Study on the Working of GNN and CNN on Panoramic X-Rays in Prediction of Dental Diseases. In 2023 8th International Conference on Communication and Electronics Systems (ICCES)

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **Title: Detection of Dental Diseases using Deep Learning**

Duration: August 2022 - May 2023 ; Team Size: 4

Brief Description: By employing sophisticated deep learning models such as Convolutional Neural Networks (CNN) and Graph Neural Networks (GNN), we aim to create a highly accurate and efficient Al-driven solution for early disease detection.

#### Individual Role:

- Reviewed two influential research papers, extracting insights to inform our project's direction
- Crafted an intuitive web application interface for seamless user interaction
- Contributed to implementing CNN in the project's back end. Fine-tuning its architecture improved predictive precision

## **Title: Facial Emotion Detection with Computer Vision**

Duration: August – September 2022 ; Team Size: 3

Brief Description: Developed an emotion detection system that utilizes facial expressions and movements which played a crucial role in gauging customer sentiment towards goods or services and significantly influencing customer-personnel interactions.

Individual Role:

- Data pre-processing, image augmentation, and feature extraction
- · Training, and validation using Convolutional Neural Networks

## Title: Share Ride Application in Django Framework

Duration: February – April 2022 ; Team Size: 5

Brief Description: Share Ride Application (SRA) is intended to help the user to share car rides with other users traveling on the same route.

#### Individual Role:

- · Conducting an extensive literature review by delving into existing research and insights
- Contributed valuable knowledge to inform and enrich the project's design and implementation
- Visually shaping our project through essential diagrams including class diagrams, data flow diagrams, and use case diagrams

## Title: Memotion using NLP

Duration: February - April 2022; Team Size: 3

Brief Description: Sentiment analysis for memes For Image captioning, using 2 models (for image caption and second for text classification)

#### Individual Role:

- · Implemented code or Image captioning,
- Used 2 models, Inception V3 (for feature extraction) and Recurrent neural network (for predicting the next word from sequence and feed forward network)

## VOLUNTEERING/COMMUNITY SERVICE

#### Served as a Social Media Research Intern at People For Animals (NGO) 2022, India

Facilitating research for the establishment of a robust network to support lobbying initiatives for animal-rights.

# Conducted a session on 'Cyber Crimes' as part of Student Social Responsibility at Amrita Vishwa Vidyapeetham, India

For raising awareness among youth about the intricacies and potential threats of online security.

#### **SKILLS**

**Research Skills:** User studies (design experiments (structured and semi-structured study design, quantitative, qualitative and mixed-method data analysis, systematic literature review and survey

Visualization Skills: Tableau

Front-end Web Dev Skills: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3

Back-end Web Dev Skills: Java Databases: SQL Based (MySQL)

Data Science & Applied M.L.: Python (NumPy, Pandas, scikit-learn), JavaScript (TensorFlow.js)

**Document Creation:** Microsoft and Google Office Suites, LaTex, Markdown Graphics

Languages: English, Hindi, Telugu